[MUSIC]
[음악]
Okay. Well, we've talked quite extensively about
회귀분석을 통한 주택 가치 예측을
using regression for the task of predicting house value, but of course,
꽤 상세히 다뤘는데 회귀분석은
the number of applications in which regression can be used are quite large.
다른 다양한 분야에도 응용될 수 있습니다
Let's discuss just a few examples.
몇몇 예를 들어보죠
So one is for
하나는
predicting your salary after you take this Machine Learning specialization.
이 기계학습 특화과정을 마친 후 받게 될 연봉 예측입니다
So you work really, really hard in this specialization, and
이 특화과정을 열심히 공부해서
hopefully after that, you can go earn a really cool job, have a very big salary.
멋진 직장을 잡아 아주 높은 연봉을 받게 된다고 하죠
But to predict how much your salary will be, maybe that depends on things like,
하지만 정확히 얼마가 될지는 여러 가지에
what was your performance in the various courses of the specialization?
좌우될 수 있는데 특화과정 내 여러 수업에서의 성적은 어떠했는지와
What was the quality of your capstone project?
캡스톤 프로젝트의 품질이 어떠했는지
How many forum responses did you make?
포럼 답글은 몇 개 썼는지
And so on.
이렇습니다
Okay. When we think about predicting your
연봉 y 모자를 예측할 때
salary, y hat What we're gonna do is we're gonna estimate our model parameters, w0,
각각 절편과 수업 성적, 캡스톤 프로젝트 품질,
w1, w2 and w3, which are our intercept and our weights on your performance in
포럼 참여도 성적 가중치를 나타내는
the class, the quality of your capstone, and your participation in the forum.
모델 파라미터 w0, w1, w2, w3를 예측합니다
And when we're estimating these model parameters, what we're gonna use,
모델 파라미터를 예측할 때
we're gonna use these features for other students who have taken this course and
과거 수업을 들었던
the observations of what their salaries were and
다른 학생의 연봉이 어땠는지,
the jobs they got after taking this Machine Learning Specialization.
어떤 직장을 잡았는지 관찰결과를 살펴봅니다
Another application of regression is for doing stock prediction.
회귀분석은 주가 예측에도 적용됩니다
So here, we might think about the fact that the prediction for
내일 주가는 최근 주가의 움직임에
the price of a stock tomorrow depends on the recent history of the stock price.
연관되어 있을지도 모릅니다
It depends on news events, different things going on in the world,
뉴스, 세계에서 벌어지는 여러 사건,
as well as the value of other related commodities.
관련 원자재 가격 등에 연동됩니다
And a very different application than thinking about predicting stock prices or
주가 예측이나 특화과정 수료 후 연봉과 아주 다른
your salary after this specialization is you're sitting on Twitter,
영역의 응용을 예로 들자면 트위터에서
you tweet something, and
트윗을 했을 때
you wanna know how many people are gonna eventually retweet what you just tweeted.
몇 명이 최종적으로 방금한 트윗을 리트윗할지를 들 수 있습니다
Well, this might depend on how many followers you have, how many followers
추종자 숫자와 추종자의 추종자 숫자,
your followers have, different features of the text of what you tweeted,
트윗한 텍스트의 여러 특징,
the popularity of the hashtag you included,
해시태그의 인기도,
number of past retweets of your tweets that you've had, and things like this.
과거 트윗의 리트윗 숫자 등에 달려있을지 모릅니다
And it turns out these types of models can actually be really good at predicting
이런 형식의 모델은 트윗의 최종 리트윗
the eventual number of retweets of your tweet.
숫자 예측을 꽤 정확히 해냅니다
And another very different application is maybe you have a smart house,
또 다른 응용을 들자면 스마트 하우스가 있어
there's lots of different sensors in this house, and
엄청난 수의 센서가 달렸는데
lots of different things you can control like temperature settings in different
이를 통해 여러 장소의 온도 조절, 통풍구,
locations, vents, window blinds, and things like this.
창문 블라인드 등을 제어할 수 있다고 칩시다
And you have a home office and you have a desk, and you wanna be able to predict
서재에 책상이 있는데 다양한 설정을 조절했을 때
what's the temperature at your desk based on various settings of all these controls.
책상 곁의 온도가 어떤지 예측하고 싶다고 합시다
But there's actually no sensor directly at your desk.
하지만 사실 책상 곁에는 센서가 없습니다
So, what you can think about doing is
그러기 위해서
fitting a spatial model in order to predict what the temperature is
공간 모델 설정으로 여러 곳의
at all these different locations throughout the house.
온도를 예측해볼 수 있습니다
And this might depend on features such as the thermostat settings in the house,
온도 조절 장치 설정, 블라인드의 개폐 여부,
whether the blinds are open or closed, temperature outside, how you've
실외 온도, 통풍구 설정, 시간대 등의
set different vents, and as well as things like the time of the day, okay?
특징에 좌우되겠지요
So, hopefully, you see that applications of regression, and
이 강의에서 다루는 회귀분석은 그저
this really just touches the tip of the iceberg of where regression is used, but
빙산의 일각만에 불과하지만 무척 강력한 도구라는
it's really quite a powerful tool.
사실을 이해하셨으면 좋겠습니다
[MUSIC]
[음악]